Browse By section Toggle navigation [Shopping Cart](https://www.ingentaconnect.com/cart;jsessionid=gjin8seqp2m4d.x-ic-live-01 "Link to Shopping Cart") login

Search 

Search by

Submit search

* [Advanced  
    Search](https://www.ingentaconnect.com/search/advanced;jsessionid=gjin8seqp2m4d.x-ic-live-01 "Link to advanced search")

* BROWSE BY:

[Home](https://www.ingentaconnect.com/;jsessionid=gjin8seqp2m4d.x-ic-live-01 "home") / IngentaConnect Help Pages

Data Privacy Statement
======================

Privacy Policy
--------------

Ingenta Connect is powered by Ingenta (UK) Ltd.

In order to download any content, excluding open access or free content, from Ingenta Connect it will be necessary for you to register with us, and it will be necessary for Ingenta to maintain personal information data records in order to supply you with the services you have requested. Services include purchase of pay-per-view articles, accessing subscribed content, purchasing print-on-demand books (where available) or other content, and setting up RSS feeds, "favourites" and new content alerts.

Any personal information you give us which are necessary to provide you with such services will be treated as confidential. When transferring such personal information to others within the EEA or other territorial area in order to provide such services, we ensure that appropriate and suitable safeguards and technical measures are in place to protect your personal data.

We will only keep records of your personal information for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes for which we have collected it, and to enable us to comply with any statutory or regulatory obligations in relation to retention of records. We respect requests to stop processing your personal data for marketing purposes.

Your Legal Rights
-----------------

You have the right to request access to and rectification or erasure of personal information, the right to restrict processing of your personal information, and the right to object to processing of your personal information. You have the right to object to your personal information being processed on the grounds of Ingenta's legitimate interests. You have the right to object to us sending you direct marketing at any time, and we will only send you direct marketing material if you have specifically asked us to do so and where we feel such material may be of genuine interest. You can contact us by email at [\[email protected\]](https://www.ingentaconnect.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) in relation to any of the rights described in this paragraph, or if you have any questions regarding this privacy policy. You have the right to lodge a complaint regarding our processing of your personal information with a data protection supervisory authority in a country where you live, work, or where you believe a breach may have occurred.

Marketing and Advertising
-------------------------

Certain selected companies advertise on the Ingenta Connect website or on the pages of certain publications that we host. If you click on such advertisements, companies and institutions advertising on Ingenta Connect may collect information, such as your IP address, while you are visiting their websites. You may be able to opt out of such advertising via settings in your browser. We are not responsible for any personal information you may give to such third-party sites.

For marketing purposes, we record the click-through rate on such advertisements. This information is not personally identifiable.

Email sent to us may not be secure. If you choose to send us an email message we may retain the content of the email, your email address and our response for the purposes of quality control. You may request that such information be deleted at any time by mailing [\[email protected\]](https://www.ingentaconnect.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), referencing the email correspondence to be deleted.

Linked Sites
------------

Ingenta Connect provides links to a variety of other Internet resources. These sites are not governed by our privacy policy and users are encouraged to view the privacy policy of such other web sites before using or providing any information to the site.

Contacting us
-------------

Ingenta is based at Suite 2, Whichford House Parkway Court John Smith Drive Oxford OX4 2JY. You can contact us regarding this privacy statement by email at [\[email protected\]](https://www.ingentaconnect.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

For immediate questions regarding any aspect of the service, including access to articles you have purchased, please go to https://www.ingentaconnect.com/about/help/index

Use of cookies
--------------

Cookies are small files, created while using a site, that enable additional functionality. They perform various functions such as saving your password, listing potential purchases in a shopping cart and saving your preferences, and are a required feature to support such personalization features on Ingenta Connect. Your browser is probably set to accept Cookies, but if you prefer not to receive Cookies you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse them. You can use our site without Cookies enabled as long as you do not want to register, sign in, or use any of the personalization features.

Date of Statement
-----------------

The date of this Privacy Statement is 18th May 2018. Ingenta encourages users of Ingenta Connect to review our Privacy Policy Statement periodically for updates. Ingenta Connect reserves the right to change its privacy policies at any time. Changes are effective when posted to this site.

Close Signup Dialog

### [Sign-in](# "sign in")

* Username: 
* Password:  
* 

 Remember Login

#### Share Content

* Access Key
* Free content
* Partial Free content
* New content
* Open access content
* Partial Open access content
* Subscribed content
* Partial Subscribed content
* Free trial content

Website © 2024 Ingenta. Article copyright remains with the publisher, society or author(s) as specified within the article.

Ingenta is not the publisher of the publication content on this website. The responsibility for the publication content rests with the publishers providing the material. Please refer to our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.ingentaconnect.com/about/terms "Terms and Conditions").

X

###### Cookie Policy

**Ingenta Connect** website makes use of cookies so as to keep track of data that you have filled in. [I am Happy with this](#) [Find out more](https://www.ingentaconnect.com/about/privacy;jsessionid=gjin8seqp2m4d.x-ic-live-01)
